Will Thompson

Contact

www.wft.wtf

+31 (0) 683 48 51 56

will.f.thompson@gmail.com

willfthompson

/willfthompson

Linnaeuskade 16-2

Amsterdam

1098 BE

Tech Stack

Ruby Intermediate

Rails Intermediate

JavaScript Intermediate

HTML Intermediate

CSS Intermediate

React Beginner

Python Beginner

C Beginner

Skills

Project F Management S

Product Strategy

Communications Growth

Data Analytics Agile/Sprint

Bio

I've been working with – and within – technology companies for the past decade, helping to prove how products impact users. I've recently taken some time out to improve my software development skills, and in September, completed an intensive three-month full-stack web development bootcamp.

I now want to use both sets of skills to build efficient products that solve user problems simply and clearly.

Experience

OnePlus - Head of Integrated Marketing, Benelux

2019-2020 Amsterdam

- Created the launch strategy for H1 2020 product line up
- Project managed H1 2020 product line-up launch across ATL, Digital,
 PR, Social and Digital channels
- Developed and implemented marketing strategies that utilise
 OnePlus's strength across all marketing channels

OnePlus – Europe Communications Manager -> Head of Communications, Europe

2018-2020 London/Amsterdam

- Analysed European media feedback to create meaningful insights into future product strategies
- Developed product messaging alongside product development teams and ensured consistency from spokespeople across Europe.
- Built and managed a team of 14 across 14 countries
- Planned and executed proactive and creative PR campaigns to maintain consistent brand visibility outside of launch periods

Octopus Group - Senior Account Manager

2017-2018 London

• Worked with a range of B2B clients to achieve business goals through communications campaigns

Dynamo PR- Account Executive -> Senior Account Manager

2013-2017 London

- Raised over \$10m for crowdfunding campaigns including notable campaigns 3Doodler, Gramovox and M3D
- Launched Ubuntu's first consumer offering, Ubuntu Touch.
- Built & launched a solid gold HTC One
- Created the Vive Everest event, an experience featuring wind machines, real snow and ski-wear. Resulting in the BBC naming 2017 as 'the year of VR'

Interests



One More Thing

I once drove a 20-year-old Skoda from London to Ulaanbaatar (that's in Mongolia!)

Education

University of West England

BSc(Hons) Audio Technology 2007-2010 Bristol

- Covered audio programming, manipulating signal inputs to create new and interesting sounds.
- For my dissertation I designed and programmed a phase vocoder, a programme to manipulate both frequency and time domains through phase state.
- Learnt programming fundamentals in C - including a whole module on boolean logic.

Le Wagon

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp 2020 Amsterdam

- Nine week programme, covering Ruby, Rails, Javascript and HTML/CSS resulting in an MVP
- Created final project boomzy.me. A new way to connect older people with skills with younger people who want to learn.
- Full-fledged platform featuring live-chat and video calling.